Guide to the William Henry Miller miscellany, 1879-1916.
Miller, William Henry miscellany
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
William Henry Miller miscellany, 1879-1916.
2811
William Henry, Miller, 1848-1922.
.4 cubic ft.
Printed materials, plans.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes drawings and blueprints for Cornell buildings, including Sage infirmary medical building and the Cascadilla School in Ithaca, New York; unidentified drawings; details of two fireplaces in the Ithaca Conservatory of Music (now Ithaca College); two small hand carved wooden panels presented by Miller to the College of Architecture at the time of its semi-centennial (1921); a scrapbook of clippings and plates from architectural magazines; a book of architectural postcards, including some depicting Miller's buildings; account books with Gauntlett and Brooks, pertaining to the Fiske House of Jennie McGraw Fiske; two letters from Andrew Dickson White to Miller, 1870, 1896; and correspondence relating to the construction of the kitchen in Prudence Risley Hall, including letters to E.L. Williams (Cornell University Treasurer) from Miller, Thomas Tree (Manager of Sage College), and Flora Rose, 1913.
Also, plans and specifications for addition to President White's house, 1895, with comments by Andrew Dickson White (12 items).
A letter possibly to William Henry Miller from his mother, 1879.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
William Henry Miller was an Ithaca, New York architect. He designed several Cornell University buildings, including Uris Library. He was a member of the Cornell Class of 1872.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes drawings and blueprints for Cornell buildings, including Sage infirmary medical building and the Cascadilla School in Ithaca, New York; unidentified drawings; details of two fireplaces in the Ithaca Conservatory of Music (now Ithaca College); two small hand carved wooden panels presented by Miller to the College of Architecture at the time of its semi-centennial (1921); a scrapbook of clippings and plates from architectural magazines; a book of architectural postcards, including some depicting Miller's buildings; account books with Gauntlett and Brooks, pertaining to the Fiske House of Jennie McGraw Fiske; two letters from Andrew Dickson White to Miller, 1870, 1896; and correspondence relating to the construction of the kitchen in Prudence Risley Hall, including letters to E.L. Williams (Cornell University Treasurer) from Miller, Thomas Tree (Manager of Sage College), and Flora Rose, 1913.
Also, plans and specifications for addition to President White's house, 1895, with comments by Andrew Dickson White (12 items).
A letter possibly to William Henry Miller from his mother, 1879.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Miller, William Henry, 1848-1922.; White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918.; Rose, Flora, 1874-; Tree, Thomas.; Williams, E. L.; Fiske, Jennie McGraw, 1840-1881.; Fiske, Jennie McGraw, 1840-1881; Rose, Flora, 1874-; Tree, Thomas; White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918; Williams, E. L.; Cascadilla School (Ithaca, N.Y.); Cornell University -- Buildings.; Fiske House (Ithaca, N.Y.); Gauntlett and Brooks (Ithaca, N.Y.); Cascadilla School (Ithaca, N.Y.); Cornell University
Subjects:
Architecture, Domestic -- United States.; Architecture -- Ithaca.; Kitchens -- Ithaca.; Architects.; Architecture; Buildings; Kitchens
Places:
New York (State) -- Ithaca; United States
Form and Genre Terms:
Architectural drawings.; Postcards.; Account books.; Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Building plans (Mapcase Folder 1 and 6) are restricted to permission of the office of Planning Design and Construction.
RELATED MATERIALS
See also: Heller House Records, #15-4-1886.
See also: William Henry Miller papers, #1856.
CONTAINER LIST
- Architectural Post Card Collection, Undated (Box 1)
- Correspondence A.D. White and Mrs. Miller, 1878-1896-06-05 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Prudence Risley Hall Correspondence, 1913-04-09-1913-06-02 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Account Booklets (Fiske House, 32 Eddy St, Price Plaining Mill), 1880-1881 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Veranda and Carriage Porch Plan and Elevation A.D. White House, Undated (Folder 1)
  Restricted to permission of the office of Planning Design and Construction
- Photocopy Transverse Section Through Main Hall Looking West Uris Library, 1889-06-01 (Folder 1)
- Mantel Details Conservatory of Music, 1894-05-30 (Folder 1)
- Unknown Plan, Undated (Folder 1)
- North and South Elevation Jacob Cram's Residence, Undated (Folder 2)
- East and West Elevation Jacob Cram's Residence, Undated (Folder 2)
- Interior Sectional Elevation Hall Looking Toward Fire Place Jacob Cram's Residence, Undated (Folder 2)
- Foundation Plan Jacob Cram's Residence, Undated (Folder 2)
- Basement Plan Jacob Cram's Residence, Undated (Folder 2)
- First Floor Plan Jacob Cram's Residence, Undated (Folder 2)
- Second Floor Plan Jacob Cram's Residence, Undated (Folder 2)
- Roof Plan Jacob Cram's Residence, Undated (Folder 2)
- Front Door and Fire Place Details Jacob Cram's Residence, Undated (Folder 2)
- Finish in Butler's Pantry Details Jacob Cram's Residence, Undated (Folder 2)
- South Side of Billard Room Details Jacob Cram's Residence, Undated (Folder 2)
- Dining Room Mantel James T. Clossen's Residence, Undated (Folder 3)
- Library Mantel Details James T. Clossen's Residence, Undated (Folder 3)
- South East Elevation James T. Clossen's Residence, Undated (Folder 3)
- South West Elevation James T. Clossen's Residence, Undated (Folder 3)
- North East Elevation James T. Clossen's Residence, Undated (Folder 3)
- Second Story Plan James T. Clossen's Residence, Undated (Folder 3)
- Ground Floor Plan James T. Clossen's Residence, Undated (Folder 3)
- Third Story Plan James T. Clossen's, Undated (Folder 3)
- Folder Manuscript Note Prof. Wait Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 4)
- Grille Detail for Inside Vestibule Door in Residence of M. E. Olmsted, Undated (Folder 4)
- Unknown Building East Elevation, Undated (Folder 4)
- Unknown Building Front Elevation, Undated (Folder 4)
- Basement Plan Warren E. Dennis Residence, 1894-09-20 (Folder 5)
- First Floor Plan Warren E. Dennis Residence, 1894-09-20 (Folder 5)
- Second Floor Plan Warren E. Dennis Residence, 1894-09-20 (Folder 5)
- North and South Elevation Warren E. Dennis Residence, 1894-09-20 (Folder 5)
- East Elevation Warren E. Dennis Residence, 1894-09-20 (Folder 5)
- Second Floor Plumbing Plan Warren E. Dennis Residence, Undated (Folder 5)
- Dining Room and Billard Room Details Warren E. Dennis Residence, 1894-09-20 (Folder 5)
- Cellar and Cold Storage Plan C.U. Medical Building, Undated (Folder 6)
- Basement Plan C.U. Medical Building, Undated (Folder 6)
- North Elevation C.U. Medical Building, Undated (Folder 6)
- West Elevation C.U. Medical Building, Undated (Folder 6)
- South Elevation C.U. Medical Building, Undated (Folder 6)
- East Elevation C.U. Medical Building, Undated (Folder 6)
- Court Elevations C.U. Medical Building, Undated (Folder 6)
- Longitudinal Section Looking South Of Basement and Cellar Through Cold Storage C.U. Medical Building, Undated (Folder 6)
- Transverse Section Looking East Through Main Entrance and Staircase C.U. Medical Building, Undated (Folder 6)
- Details of Main Entrance C.U. Medical Building, Undated (Folder 6)
- Details of Interior Finish C.U. Medical Building, Undated (Folder 6)
- Details of Interior Finish C.U. Medical Building, Undated (Folder 6)
- Front Elevation of Porch for Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Side Elevation of Porch for Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Additions to Roof Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Additions to Roof Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- West Elevation Dormitories Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- East Elevation Dormitories Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Roof Plan Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Roof Plan Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Fifth Floor Plan Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Ventilation Plan Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- East Elevation Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- South Elevation Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Front Elevation Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- North Elevation Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Basement Plan Cascadila School, Undated (Folder 7)
- First Floor Plan Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Second Floor Plan Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Third Floor Plan Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Roof Plan Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- South Elevation Dormitories Cascadilla School Blueprints, Undated (Folder 7)
- North Elevation Dormitories Cascadilla School Blueprints, Undated (Folder 7)
- West Elevation Dormitories Cascadilla School Blueprints, Undated (Folder 7)
- East Elevation Dormitories Cascadilla School Blueprints, Undated (Folder 7)
- North Elevation Photocopy Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Roof Plan Photocopy Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Basement Plan Photocopy Dormitories Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- First Floor Photocopy Dormitories Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- South Elevation Dormitories Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- North Elevation Dormitories Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- North Elevation Dormitories Cascadilla School Roof Extension, Undated (Folder 7)
- West Elevation Dormitories Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- South Elevation Dormitories Cascadilla School Extension, Undated (Folder 7)
- East Elevation Dormitories Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Basement Plan Dormitories Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- First Floor Plan Dormitories Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Second Floor Plan Dormitories Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Third Floor Plan Dormitories Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Fourth Floor Plan Dormitories Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Footings Plan Dormitories Cascadilla School, Undated (Folder 7)
- Architectural Scrap Book Encompassing News Paper Clippings of Miller's Work, Cathedral and Church Images, and Various Other Architectural Details, 1879-1916; Volume